RODOLFO D SAEZ

www.RodolfoSaez.com • github.com/rsaez • Atlanta, GA 30309 • 954.328.5362 • rolo928@gmail.com • U.S. Citizen

"Rodolfo was AMAZING. He took his time, ensured ALL of our questions were answered (even when we veered off scope), he showed genuine interest in making sure our deployment adhered to best practices."

- VMware Customer

SUMMARY

1 year in Full-Stack development using Javascript, Node.js, React.js. 12+ years of success in professional services fostering business relationships. Self-driven, organized, and passionate problem solver in all aspects of technology. Leads by example, approachable, and knows how to follow and lead a team to success.

EDUCATION

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, School of Computer Science

Atlanta, GA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Fall 2010 - Spring 2014

Threads Internetworks and Media

Full-Stack Development Web Development Certificate

July 2018

EXPERIENCE

VMWARE INC Atlanta, GA

Software Consultant

January 2015 - August 2018

- Developed innovative solutions to meet costumers' requirements and manage product issues and their resolutions.
- Lead senior executives, enterprise teams and stake holders through complex technical solutions to successful completion.
- Assisted with the planning, installation, configuration, operations, training, and integration of all network infrastructure and software in all service areas, including all relevant 3rd party technical components.

GEORGIA TECH RESEARCH INSTITUTE

Atlanta, GA

Student Research Assistant - Electro-Optical Systems Laboratory (EOSL)

April 2013 – May 2014

- Conducted analysis of electro-optical systems that spans the electromagnetic spectrum from RF through UV.
- Created procedures for parsing research data in infrared models and simulations.

REVELEX CORPORATION

Boca Raton, FL

Network Engineer

September 2008 – *July* 2010

- Installed, configured, administered, maintained, and troubleshot Cisco firewalls, routers, and switches.
- Advised, bade on, tested, and implemented new technology solutions to fulfill company's needs.

VITAS INNOVATIVE HOSPICE CARE

Miami, FL

NOC Network Analyst

September 2007 – September 2008

- Deployed and configured enterprise software to ensure HIPAA compliance is maintained in support of field staff.
- Provided and analyzed network performance data to IT Director which resulted in maximized bandwidth output.

SKILLS/INTERESTS

Projects: https://fashionzen.herokuapp.com/

Bilingual: Possess excellent oral/written communication skills in English and Spanish

Technologies: Javascript, Node.js, NPM, MongoDB, MySql, AJAX, Cloud Architecture, AirWatch, vSphere, vSAN, MDM,

IDM, SAML, HIPAA, PCI, GIT, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap

Platforms: Android, Apple iOS, Windows Phone, Cisco IOS, Windows Server, Linux, Windows NT/2000/XP/7/8/10

Workstation, Mac OS X

Networking: Cisco VPN, Firewalls, Load Balancers, TCP/IP, SNMP, DHCP, VOIP routers,

CERTS: CompTIA Security+, Network+, Cybersecurity Analyst+; VMware Enterprise Mobility Expert, VCA6 DCV **Affiliations:** Society of Hispanic Professional Engineers, Hispanic Organization for Promoting Education, Salsa Dancer

Possess active "SECRET" DoD security clearance

MILITARY EXPERIENCE

UNITED STATES ARMY – 1st Lieutenant – Battalion Security Officer

2001 – Present

- Build relations with multinational, multicomponent, multiservice organizations to achieve mission success.
- Set initial standards to meet policies and procedures set by DOD and US Army.
- Continually provide a composite risk assessment to prevent the loss of life and sensitive items.
- Supervise a platoon of 64 soldiers ensuring continuous military bearing and soldier readiness.
- Paratrooper for 82nd Airborne Division; US Rapid Deployment Force; 2003 -2004 OIF & OEF